# FERNANDA BRITO

Dublin | +351 0851309371 | fernandabritobio@gmail.com | No sponsorship required

### **SUMMARY**

I am a Software Developer Student looking for an entry-level development position. Graduated in Science and holding a Multimedia Master Degree, I had been working for more than 5 years as a Science Teacher. I moved to Ireland in 2020 and decided to go deeper into tech that I love and seek a new path in IT.

Quick learner passionate about development, I am a supportive and enthusiastic team player dedicated to efficiently developing projects with the ability and willingness to innovate and learn new technologies.

#### **EDUCATION**

### UNIVERSITY COLLEGE DUBLIN (UCD)

Software Development Professional Course

Dublin, Ireland Expected March 2022

### PORTO UNIVERSITY FACULTY OF ENGINEERING (FEUP)

Multimedia (Instructional Design) Master's Degree.

Porto, Portugal Sep 2010 - Sep 2012

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

SÃO BENTO INSTITUTE

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Adjunct Professor

Jul 2015 – Dec 2019

- Collected and analysed data to identify and resolve potential educational problems;
- Experienced in create, modify and moderate science content on LMS in collaboration with different teams;
- Mentor new students, coaching them to achieve their best results;
- Facilitated deadlines within a master schedule to meet expectations of the education department;
- Compile educational data from different sources and prepare a summarized report;
- Communicate information with clarity to keep customers/parents updated.

## RIO DE JANEIRO CITY HALL

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Adjunct Professor

Dec 2012 – Dec 2019

- Developed methods to optimize personal growth, contemplating and understanding learner's capabilities;
- The success of education services resulted from my ability to contribute skills, knowledge, share extensive experiences and administer technology skills.

### RIO DE JANEIRO STATE UNIVERSITY

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

I. Substitute Professor

Apr 2013 – Jul 2015

- Supported customized curriculum and learning materials creation;
- Conducted ongoing program evaluations to ensure the effectiveness of the learning process;
- Planned and guided professional development activities for teachers to be.

### II. Professor Assistant

Apr 2009 – Jul 2010

• Assist to develop methods to assess learning programs and delivery, improving learning effectiveness.

### SCIENCE AND EDUCATION RESEARCH CENTRE

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Associate Researcher

Apr 2010 - Dec 2015

- Creative media designer experienced in the development of multimedia products to include video products and training curriculum packages.
- Proficient in collecting and analyzing data to identify video issues and potential errors.
- Responsible for the design and execution of e-learning courses using technology-enhanced learning (TEL).

COVID-19 VACCINES May 2021

From conceptual ideas through code logic implementation, I built this website to help elucidate people on how vaccines works, their importance in World's Health and the main differences between the Covid-19 vaccine's types and efficacy.

During project development, I used Balsamiq wireframes to guide the interface development process using best practices and heuristics for better user experience; Page layout, colour and typography were researched previously to assure implements UX best practices and consistency along with pages. Content is backed by reliable sources to build trust and deliver accurate data about Covid-19 vaccines. I tested all pages with W3C and Jigsaw validator to ensure the website runs without any major defects. I have also certified the website is accessible using Web Accessibility Evaluation Tool (Wave).

**Technologies:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery.

**Live site:** https://nandabritto.github.io/Covid-19-vaccines-Milestone-1/ **Github:** https://github.com/nandabritto/Covid-19-vaccines-Milestone-1

WHERE IS BILLY?

Jun 2021

I built an interactive quiz to test user geolocation and landmarks knowledge. During project development, I set content goals and created wireframes making attention catching. Page layout was designed to make the game mobile friendly and based on UX best practices. Mainly using JavaScript, I developed some interesting features like a countdown timer to each question, a modal popup with an explanation about the question and Google Maps API displaying correct location when the answer is wrong, as well ranking functionality (using internal storage). Tests were done using W3C, Jigsaw validators and Wave assuring that no bugs were left before the release date.

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.

**Live site:** https://nandabritto.github.io/MS2/ **Github:** https://github.com/nandabritto/MS2

SEARCH YOUR BRAND Jul 2021

During this project I designed and developed a command-line application to allow users to retrieve tweets (using Twitter API) and export outputs into Google Spreadsheets, allowing easy data analysis further. This application is written in Python with some libraries such as Pandas, for dataframe creation and data preparation, Geopy, for user geolocation creation, and Gspread, for Google API and exporting prepared data into spreadsheets. Since this command line application relies on external sources, errorhandling code was added to ensure that all errors are caught and an appropriate error message is provided. I tested the application code using PEP8 reassuring that no bugs are present on the final version. This application is deployed on Heroku.

**Technologies and libraries:** Python, Twitter, Google Spreadsheets and Google Drive API, Pandas, Gspread, Geopy and Heroku.

Live site: https://search-your-brand.herokuapp.com/

Github: https://github.com/nandabritto/search\_your\_brand

### **VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES**

#### **CARLOW VOLUNTEER CENTRE**

Volunteer User Testers Jun 2021

- Support Volunteer User Acceptance Testers to test the registration process and ensure it is clear, user-friendly and efficient.
- Carried out user acceptance testing by running through the sign-up process, identifying any areas of confusion and providing feedback about the application.

### **ADDITIONAL**

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Bootstrap, Google Developers Tools, LMS. Certifications & Training: 5 days Coding Challenge (Code Institute), Articulate 360(LinkedIn), Data Science Visualisation (HarvardX), Data Science: R Basics (HarvardX), Introduction to Game Localization(Udemy) and Localisation Essentials (Udacity).